In this video we are going to continue our discussion on global data flow analysis by
在本视频中，我们将通过以下方式继续讨论全局数据流分析
taking a look at how global constant propagation works in detail. To begin,
详细了解一下全局常量传播是如何工作的。首先，
let's review what the conditions are to do global constant propagation. So to replace
让我们回顾一下做全局常数传播的条件是什么。所以要替换掉
a use of a variable x by a constant k, we have to know the following property. That
当变量x被常数k使用时，我们必须知道以下性质。那
on, that on every path to the use of x, the last assignment to the variable x is,
在使用x的每条路径上，变量x的最后一个赋值是，
x equals the constant k, okay? And this has to be true again on every path to the
X等于常数k，好吗？在通往世界的每一条道路上，这一点都必须是正确的。
use of x. Now, global constant propagation can be performed at any point where this
使用x。现在，全局常量传播可以在此位置的任何点执行
property holds. What we're going to look at in this video, is the case of computing
财产保有。我们将在这段视频中看到的是计算机的情况
the property for a single variable x at all program points. So we're going to take
所有程序点的单个变量x的属性。所以我们要把
one, we're going to focus on one variable x and we're going to compute whether it's
首先，我们将重点放在一个变量x上，然后我们将计算它是否
a constant at every program point. It's easy to extend the algorithm to compute
每个程序点的常量。该算法易于扩展，便于计算
this property for all variables. One very simple but very efficient way to do that
所有变量的此属性。要做到这一点，有一种非常简单但非常有效的方法
is just to repeat the computation once for each variable in the method body. The way
只需对方法体中的每个变量重复计算一次。这条路
we are going to compute the information that we want is to associate one of the
我们将计算我们想要的信息，将其中一个
following values with the variable x at every point in the program. And, let's
在程序中的每一点用变量x追随值。还有，让我们
start with the last one here we will assign x this special value here which is
从这里的最后一个开始，我们将在这里为x指定这个特定值，它是
pronounced top if x is not a constant. So if we can't figure out whether x is a
如果x不是常量，则读作top。所以如果我们不能确定x是否是
constant at a particular point in the program, then we'll just say x is top at
常量，那么我们就说x在
that point. And, this is going to be our safe situation. It's always okay to say we
这一点。而且，这将是我们的安全状况。我们总是可以说我们
don't know what the value of x is and when we say that x has a value top, and we
我不知道x的值是多少，当我们说x有一个值顶的时候，我们
could say, we, we were essentially saying we don't know whether x is a constant or
可以说，我们，我们本质上是说我们不知道x是常数还是
not at this point in the program, x could have any value. Alright? Now, another
在程序的这一点上不是，x可以有任何值。好吗？现在，又来了一个
possibility is that we will say that x is some constant c, okay? So this is a
可能我们会说x是某个常数c，好吗？所以这是一个
particular constant and if we say that x is a constant c at a program point, that
特定的常数，如果我们说x是某个程序点的常数c，那么
means, in fact, at that program point, we believe o r we have proven that x is
意思是，实际上，在那个程序点上，我们相信或者我们已经证明了x是
always that constant. Now, there is a third possibility which is not immediately
总是这样不变。现在，还有第三种可能性，但不是马上
intuitive, perhaps. But, as we will see, plays a very important role in algorithms
也许是直觉上的。但是，正如我们将看到的，在算法中扮演着非常重要的角色
for, for global constant propagation. And in fact, in all global data flow analysis,
对于，对于全局常量传播。事实上，在所有的全球数据流分析中，
and that is bottom, okay? So this value is pronounced bottom and intuitively the idea
这是最低点，好吗？所以这个值发音为Bottom，直观地说就是这个概念
anyway that is kind of opposite of top, alright? And the interpretation of bottom
不管怎么说，这是与TOP相反的，好吗？以及对“底”的解读
is going to be that this statement never executes, alright? So, when we don't know
就是这个语句永远不会执行，好吗？所以，当我们不知道
whether a statement is even executed at all we will say that x at that point has a
无论语句是否执行，我们都会说x在那个点上有一个
value bottom. Meaning that, as far as we know that point in the program is never
值最低。也就是说，据我们所知，程序中的这一点永远不会
reached. It doesn't matter what the value of x is at that point because that
已到达。在那个点上x的值是多少并不重要，因为
statement never executes. Alright, so we're going to assign x one of these three
语句永远不会执行。好的，我们把x分配给这三个中的一个
kinds of values. Either bottom, some constant, or top. Let's begin by working
各种价值观。要么是底部、某个常量，要么是顶部。让我们从工作开始吧
through an example by hand and our goal is going to be for every program point to
通过一个手工示例，我们的目标是为每个程序点
decide whether x could be a constant definitely not a constant, or whether we
决定x是否可以是一个常数，而不是一个常数，或者我们
think that statement might not ever execute, okay? So, execution will begin at
我觉得那句话可能永远不会执行，好吗？所以，行刑将从
the top of this control flip graph. So this the entry point and before executions
此控件翻转图形的顶部。所以这是行刑前的入口点
begins, we don't anything about the value of x. So, I'm not making any assumptions
开始，我们没有关于x的值的任何东西，所以，我不做任何假设
about what code came before this basic block and so to be safe, I will say that
关于这个基本挡路之前的代码，为了安全起见，我会说
at this point, x has some unknown value. We don't know what the value of x is, it
在这一点上，x有一些未知值。我们不知道x的值是多少，是吗？
could be anything. So x = T, is the property that we want entry to the first
可能是任何东西。所以x=T，是我们想要输入到第一个
basic block. Now after the assignment x = three, that was indicated there, where
基本挡路。现在，在赋值x=3之后，这是在那里显示的，其中
what point we're talking about. So, after the assignment x = three, we'll definitely
我们谈论的是什么观点。所以，在赋值x=3之后，我们肯定会
will know that x is the constant three. Alright, now there's something here that's
就会知道x是常数3。好的，现在这里有一些东西
worth pointing out which is that our program points, the points that we're
值得一提的是，我们的程序点，我们正在
attaching this knowledge to or these, these facts to are in between the statem
将此知识附加到或这些，这些事实处于状态之间
ents. So, when I say x = three at this program point, what I mean is that after
恩茨。所以，当我在这个程序点上说x=3的时候，我的意思是在
x, after this assignment has executed, x = three, but before this predicate of the
x，在执行此赋值之后，x=3，但在
conditional has executed, I know that x = three, okay? So, the program points are in
有条件的已经执行了，我知道x=3，好吗？所以，程序点在
between statements and there's a program point before and after every statement.
在语句之间，每条语句前后都有一个程序点。
Alright, so the next thing that happens is this conditional branch. Notice that the
好的，接下来发生的就是这个条件分支。请注意，
branch doesn't update x, doesn't even refer to x so after the branch executes
分支不更新x，甚至不引用x，所以在分支执行之后
we'll definitely knows that x = three on both branches. Alright, now let's do the
我们肯定知道在两个分支上x=3。好的，现在我们来做
right hand branch. The next thing that happens is the assignment to y that would
右手分支。接下来发生的事情是对y的赋值，该赋值将
not affect the value of x. So after the assignment to y, we'll still know that x =
不会影响x的值。所以在对y赋值之后，我们仍然知道x=
three, alright? Now let's take a look at the left hand branch so the first thing
三个，好吗？现在让我们看看左边的分支，所以第一件事
that happens over here is another assignment to y. Well that won't affect
发生在这里的是y的另一项任务，这不会影响
the value of x. After the assignment of Y we'll know that x = three. And now comes
x的值。在Y赋值之后，我们就知道x=3。现在又来了
to the assignment of x, alright. So after this assignment happens at this program
对于x的赋值，好的。所以在这个项目完成这项任务之后
point we're going to know that the value of x is different. We're going to know
这一点，我们将会知道，x的值是不同的。我们就会知道
that x = four, alright. So, now after this statement we know x = four and after this
x=4，好的。现在，在这个陈述之后，我们知道x=4，在这个之后
statement over here we know x = three, alright? Now what do we know then about
在这里我们知道x=3，好吗？那么我们现在知道些什么呢？
what happens before this statement, okay? The a = two x and I just want to point
在这份声明之前会发生什么，好吗？a=2x，我只想指出
out here. I said that there's a program point before and after every statement And
在外面。我说每个语句前后都有一个程序点，
so this program point here, which is before this assignment to a is different
所以这里的这个程序点，在这个赋值给a之前是不同的
from the program points that are after x = four and y = zero. So intuitively, after x
从x=4和y=0之后的程序点。所以直观地说，在x之后
= four we know that we're still on this path over here on the left and so we know
=4我们知道我们仍然在左边的这条路上，所以我们知道
that x = four and over here after y = zero, we still know that we're on this
x=4，这里y=0之后，我们仍然知道我们在这上面
path is x = three. But, when we reach the point before a = two x, we no longer
路径是x=3。但是，当我们到达a=2x之前的点时，我们就不再
know which path we're coming from. This is the point of the merge of these two paths
知道我们从哪条路来。这是这两条路径的合并点
that both lead to this statement. And what can we say about the value of x here?
这两件事都导致了这份声明。那么，关于x的值，我们能说些什么呢？
Well, there is no constant that we can assign to x because on o ne path x is
我们没有可以赋给x的常量，因为在一条路径上x是
three and on the other path, x is four. And so what we have to say here is that
在另一条路径上，x是4。所以我们在这里要说的是
before this assignment executes, a = x, sorry, x = T. We don't know what the value
在此赋值执行之前，a=x，抱歉，x=T。我们不知道
of x is. Another way of saying it is we know we, we don't know that x is a
就是。换句话说，我们知道我们，我们不知道x是一个
constant, alright. So, after the assignment executes it doesn't affect the
常量，好的。因此，在执行赋值之后，它不会影响
value of x, we will also have that x = T. Now notice that once we have the global
值，我们也会得到x=T。现在请注意，一旦我们有了全局
constant information, once we know for every program point, what the state of x
常量信息，一旦我们知道了每个程序点，x的状态是什么
is, it's going to be very easy to perform the optimization. We simply look at the
就是，执行优化将会非常容易。我们只需查看
information associated with the statement and then it will tell us whether x is a
与该语句相关联的信息，然后它将告诉我们x是否是
constant when that statement executes or not. And if x is a constant at that point,
该语句执行或不执行时的常量。如果x在那个点是一个常数，
then we can replace that use of x by the constant. And crucial question of course
然后我们可以用常量来代替x的用法。当然也是一个至关重要的问题
is how do we compute these properties. So, we did this example by hand but how in a
我们如何计算这些性质。所以，我们手工完成了这个示例，但是如何在
systematic fashion, an arbitrary control flow graph do we actually compute these
系统方式，任意控制流图，我们真的要计算这些吗
properties for x for every program point? Now we're ready to talk about data flow
每个程序点的x的属性？现在我们准备好讨论数据流了
analysis algorithms and there's one basic principle that you see in all of these
分析算法，你可以在所有这些算法中看到一个基本原则
algorithms that's worth mentioning right away. And that's that the analysis of a
值得一提的是算法。这就是对一个
complicated program can be expressed as a combination of very simple rules that
复杂的程序可以表示为非常简单的规则的组合，这些规则
relate the change in information between adjacent statements. So we're just going
将相邻语句之间的信息更改关联起来。所以我们要走了
to focus on local rules and the way we're going to build our global data flow
将重点放在本地规则和我们将构建全球数据流的方式上
analysis is actually by a combination of rules that look only at a single statement
分析实际上是通过规则的组合进行的，这些规则只关注单个语句
and its neighbors. The idea behind the rules is going to be the push or transfer
以及它的邻居。规则背后的想法将是推动或转移
information from one statement to the next And so for each statement s, we're going
信息从一条语句传递到下一条语句，因此对于每个语句s，我们将
to compute information about the value of x immediately before and after s. Remember
来计算关于紧接在s之前和之后的x值的信息。记住
that's where, those are the program points that we want to attach information to. So
这就是我们要附加信息的程序点。所以
in particular we're going to have a function C. It stands for constant
特别地，我们将有一个函数C，它代表常量
information and C will take three arguments, takes the name of the variable,
信息，而C将接受三个参数，获取变量的名称，
x. It takes the stat ement that we're talking about, the particular statement in
x，它采用我们正在讨论的统计数据，其中的特定语句
the program that we're looking at. And then either in or out and this is what
我们现在看到的这个项目。然后要么进去，要么出去，这就是
distinguishes the value of x before s executes versus the value of x after s
区分执行%s之前的x值和执行%s之后的x值。
executes. We're going to be defining a set of transfer functions that push
执行。我们将定义一组传递函数
information or transfer information from one statement to another. And in the rules
信息或将信息从一条语句传送到另一条语句。在规则中
for constant propagation we need to talk about a statement and its predecessors. So
为了不断传播，我们需要讨论语句及其前身。所以
we're going to say that every statement s has some set of immediate predecessors p1
我们会说每个语句s都有一组直接的前置语句p1
through pn, alright? So, it's either of these statements that lead in one step to
通过pn，好吗？因此，这两条陈述中的任何一条都会导致一个步骤
the statement s. Let's do our first rule. So we have a statement s and it has some
陈述是这样的。让我们来做我们的第一条规则。所以我们有一个语句%s，它有一些
set of predecessor statements, P1, P2, P3, P4. And the situation that we're
前置语句集，P1、P2、P3、P4。我们现在的情况是
interested in here is, let's assume that x is top at the program point after one of
这里感兴趣的是，让我们假设x是程序点处的顶部，在下列其中之一之后
these predecessors. So, after some predecessor, it doesn't matter which one,
这些前辈。所以，在一些前任之后，不管是哪一个，
if it happens that x is top at the program point after that predecessor, well, then x
如果恰好x在程序点处位于该前一步之后的顶端，那么，那么x
has to be top before the execution of s, okay? So that's what this rule says. It
在处决s之前必须排在首位，好吗？所以这条规则就是这么说的。它
says if the out of any predecessor for x is top, then the in of s for x is also
表示如果x的任何前身中的out是top，那么x的s的in也是。
top. Alright, and this makes sense. It says that if we don't know whether x is a
头顶。好的，这就说得通了。它说如果我们不知道x是否是一个
constant on some path that leads to s, well then, we don't know that x is a
通向s的某个路径上的常数，那么，我们不知道x是a
constant at s. Because for all we know, execution came down that particular, came
常量。因为据我们所知，行刑是从那个特定的地方开始的
from that particular predecessor and so, we can't make any prediction about whether
因此，我们不能对此做出任何预测
s is, whether x is a constant before s executes. Now let's look at another
s是，在s执行之前x是否为常量。现在我们来看另一个
situation. Let's say that x is some constant C after the execution of some
情况。让我们假设x是某个常数C，在执行了一些
predecessor. And that on a, after another predecessor a distinct predecessor x is a
前任。在a上，在另一个前身之后，截然不同的前身x是a
different constant D. So D is not equal to C. Well then what do we know about x at
不同的常数D，所以D不等于C，那么我们知道x在
the program point before s executes? Well, we don't know anything, x has to be top,
是否执行%s之前的程序点？嗯，我们什么都不知道，x必须在上面，
because we don't know which constant, s will be, since we don't know which path
因为我们不知道哪个常数s会是，因为我们不知道哪条路径
will reach s at run time. And this is the situation that we saw in the example we
将在运行时到达%s。这就是我们在示例中看到的情况
did by hand. Another possibility is that the predecessors all agree on what the
是手工完成的。另一种可能性是，前辈们都同意
value of x could be. So let's say that we have, you know, predecessor here and that
x的值可能是。所以让我们说，你知道，我们的前任在这里和那里
after it executes x is known to be the constant C and x is known to be the
在它执行之后，已知x是常数C，x是
constant C after this predecessor and x is known to be the constant C after this
在该前身之后的常数C，并且已知x是在此之后的常数C
predecessor. There's one other possibility. Let's say that after this
前任。还有一种可能性。我们假设在这之后
predecessor over here, all we know is that x is bottom, okay? And so what the rule
这里的前身，我们所知道的就是x是底部，好吗？那么规则是什么呢？
says is that if we have this situation where either x has the property bottom
意思是，如果我们有这样的情况，其中任何一个x都有属性底部
after a predecessor or all the predecessors agree on the particular
在一位或所有前任就特定事项达成一致之后
constant that x could be, then before at the program point before s executes, we
x可能是常量，那么在s执行之前的程序点，我们
know that x is going to guarantee to be the constant C. And if you think about it
知道x将保证是常数C，如果你想一想
for a second, it's easy to see why this is correct. First of all, clearly if we come
有一秒钟，很容易看出为什么这是正确的。首先，很明显如果我们来
along one of the paths where x is known to be the constant C, since they all agree
沿着其中x已知为常数C的路径之一，因为它们都一致
and then when we get to s, x will definitely have the value C. What about
当我们到s的时候，x肯定会有c的值，那么呢？
the bottom case? Well, remember what that means. That means that this statement is
最下面的箱子呢？嗯，记住那是什么意思。这意味着这句话是
never reached so there's some predecessor P here which never executes. Which means
从未达到，所以这里有一些前身P，它永远不会执行。这意味着
if P never executes then we could never reach S along this path from P. So the
如果P从不执行，那么我们永远不能从P沿着这条路径到达S。
only paths that will reach s are the ones where x is known to be a constant,
仅将到达s的路径是已知x为常数的路径，
alright? So that's why it's okay in this situation say that x, if control if
好吗？所以这就是为什么在这种情况下，假设x，如果控制
execution reaches s at all its guaranteed to reach it in a state where x is the
执行达到s保证在x是
constant C. One last possibility is let's say that x is bottom for all the
常数C。最后一种可能性是，假设x是所有
predecessors, okay? And what does that mean? Well, that means that every
前辈们，好吗？那是什么意思？嗯，这意味着每个人
predecessor of S never executes so they're all unreachable. And therefore if every
S的前身从不执行，因此它们都是不可访问的。因此如果每个人
predecessor of x never executes s itself can never execute, and so we can conclude
x的前身永远不会执行，s本身也永远不会执行，所以我们可以得出结论。
that entry to s, x is bottom. The first four rules that we just looked at relate
s的条目，x是底部。我们刚才看到的前四条规则与
the out of one statement to the in of the next. We also have to have rules that
从一个语句的输出到下一个语句的输入。我们还必须有规则，
relate the in of a statement to the out of the same statement. So we have to push
将语句的in与同一语句的out关联起来。所以我们必须推动
information from the input of a statement to the output of the same statement. So,
从语句的输入到同一语句的输出的信息。所以,
once again, there are several cases. And let's take a look at an easy one first. If
再说一次，有几个案例。让我们先来看一个简单的问题。如果
x is bottom on an entry s, if the program point before s well, that says that at
X是条目s的底部，如果s之前的程序指针很好，也就是说在
the, that s is never reached, that s never executes. And therefore, x will be bottom
那个，那是永远不会到达的，那是永远不会执行的。因此，x将是底部
after s, after s as well. So if the program point before s is never reached,
在s之后，也在s之后。因此如果s之前的程序点从未到达，
the program point after s definitely can't be reached either. Another possibility is
s之后的程序点肯定也达不到。另一种可能性是
that we're assigning x to constant C in this statement. In that case the out of
在这条语句中，我们将x赋给常数C。在这种情况下，不在的情况下
the statement is going to be equal to C. Alright, so it doesn't matter what the
该语句将等于C。好的，因此
state of x was before the statement, after we execute the statement, x will be the
x的状态在语句之前，在我们执行语句之后，x将是
constant C. And I should say there is a conflict with the previous rule. Okay, it
常量C，我应该说这与之前的规则有冲突。好的，它
could be that x is bottom, before the statement. So rule six, has lower priority
可能是x在语句之前是底部。因此，规则6具有较低优先级
than rule five. So we, so if we could say that x is bottom after the statement, we
比第五条规则更重要。所以我们，所以如果我们可以说x是语句后面的底部，我们
would prefer you to say that so rule five would be applied first, and then if rule
我更希望你这样说，所以第五条规则将首先适用，然后如果规则
five does not apply. So if x is some other constant D or x = T, then we would apply
五个不适用。因此，如果x是其他常数D或x=T，那么我们将应用
this rule and we would conclude that x is the constancy afterwards and that makes
这条规则，我们会得出结论，x是之后的常量，这使得
sense. If x is d or x is the, is top that means that control, as far as we know, can
理智。如果x是d，或者x是顶部，这意味着，就我们所知，控件可以
reach this statement. And then what we're saying here is that well, after the
达成这一声明。然后我们在这里说的是，在
execution of this statement, if control can reach this statement after the
方法之后，如果控制可以到达此语句，则执行此语句
execution of it, x is guaranteed to be the constant C. Another possibility is that we
执行它，x保证是常数C。另一种可能是我们
have an assignment to x but the right hand side is more complicated than a constant.
对x进行赋值，但是右侧比常量复杂得多。
So this case is for everything other than the constant assignment. Okay, so this F
所以这种情况适用于除常量赋值之外的所有情况。好的，所以这个F
here just stands for some more complicated expression than just a simple constant.
这里只代表一些比简单常量更复杂的表达式。
And in this case we, we're just going to say we don't know what the value is, we're
在这种情况下我们，我们只能说我们不知道它的价值是什么，我们
not going to try to guess what the result of that computation is and we'll just say
不去尝试猜测计算的结果，我们就说
that x = T. X, w e don't know what the value of x is after the execution of this
那个x=T.x，我们不知道这个执行后x的值是多少
statement. And once again, rule five takes precedence so if rule five applies, then
声明。再一次，第五条规则优先，所以如果第五条规则适用，那么
we would apply then, then we would use that rule instead of rule seven. But, if
然后我们会应用，然后我们会使用那个规则而不是规则七。但是，如果
control can reach this statement, so up here x = C or x = T. Then we'll apply rule
控件可以达到此语句，因此在这里x=C或x=T，然后我们将应用规则
seven and conclude that x is top after the statement. And finally Rule eight, another
7，并在语句后得出x是顶部的结论。最后是第八条规则，另一条
possibility is that we're assigning to some variable other than x. And in that
可能是我们给x以外的某个变量赋值。
case, if x = k before the statement then we just keep that value. Okay, so whatever
在这种情况下，如果在语句前x=k，那么我们就保留这个值。好的，所以不管怎样
x was before the statement bottom, a constant or top, if the assignment is to
X在语句Bottom之前，如果赋值为，则为常量或TOP
some other variable other than x then x will have the same property after the
除x以外的某些其他变量在x之后将具有相同的属性
statement executes. Now, we can put these rules together into an algorithm. For
语句执行。现在，我们可以将这些规则放到一个算法中。为
every entry point, for every entry, statement to the program, we're going to
程序的每个入口点，每个条目，每个语句，我们都要
say on entry that we don't know anything about the value of x. So the program point
在条目上说我们对x的值一无所知。所以程序指针
before that entry point we're gonna say that x has an unknown value, top. And then
在这个入口点之前，我们会说x有一个未知值，top。然后
everywhere else we're going to say that the value of x, is bottom, okay. And this
在其他任何地方，我们都会说x的值是最低的，好的。还有这个
is actually important so we're going, what this intuitively is doing is its saying
实际上很重要，所以我们要去，直观地说这是在做什么
well, as far as we know except for the entry point to the program, which can
嗯，据我们所知，除了程序的入口点，它可以
definitely be executed, we don't know whether any of the other statements in the
肯定会被执行，我们不知道
control flow graph are actually ever executed and so we're going to assume
实际上曾经执行过控制流图，所以我们假设
initially, that they're not. And we're just going to say that x has the value
起初，他们不是。我们只想说x的值是
bottom everywhere except at an entry point And now what we're going to do is a kind
除了入口点以外的任何地方都是底部，现在我们要做的是一种
of constraint satisfaction algorithm. We're going to pick some statement that
约束满足算法。我们将挑选一些语句，
doesn't satisfy one of the rules, one through eight. And then we're going to
不符合其中一条规则，从一到八。然后我们要去
update it using the appropriate rules. So we'll look for places in the control flow
使用适当的规则更新它。因此，我们将在控制流中查找位置
graph where the information is inconsistent according to the rules and
根据规则信息不一致的图，以及
then we'll update, the information to make it consistent with the rules. Let's take a
然后我们会更新信息，使其符合规则。让我们拿一张
look at our example again. So, we're going to start out by saying x = T at the entry
再看看我们的例子。所以，我们首先在入口处说x=T
point, and then we're going to have all of our other program points And let me
点，然后我们将有我们所有的其他程序点，让我
indicate them here. Okay, so these are all the other program points that we have to
把他们指到这里。好的，这些都是我们必须要做的其他程序点
be concerned with. And there again, there's a program point before and after
关心……再说一遍，在这之前和之后都有一个节目点
every statement. And we are going to say the x = bottom for all of these. So, again
每一份声明。我们会说所有这些的x=Bottom。所以，再一次
what this means is, that as far as we know, control doesn't reach any of these
这意味着，据我们所知，控制权并不能到达其中的任何一个
points. We have not yet proven to ourselves that any of these statements can
分数。我们还没有向自己证明这些陈述中的任何一个都可以
execute. And now we just look around in the program and try to find places, where
执行。现在我们只是在程序中四处看看，试着找到一些地方，
the information is inconsistent according to the rules, and then we update the
根据规则信息不一致，然后我们更新
information. Let me switch colors here. So, when we begin, the information is
信息。让我在这里换一下颜色。所以，当我们开始的时候，信息是
consistent everywhere except at this first statement because if x is T before and
除了这第一个语句之外，所有地方都是一致的，因为如果x在和之前是T
we're assigning x to value three. Well, then we should not have x = bottom as the
我们将x赋给值3。那么我们不应该把x=Bottom作为
result. In fact this should be x = three. It should be the appropriate information
结果。实际上，这应该是x=3。它应该是适当的信息
here and once we update that, then we see that this next statement is inconsistent
在这里，一旦我们更新了它，我们就会看到下一条语句是不一致的
because now we know this statement is reachable. We have a statement here and
因为现在我们知道这个声明是可以实现的。我们这里有一份声明
we're concluding that the point after is not reachable which is not, not correct
我们得出的结论是，后面的点是不能到达的，这是不，不正确的
according to the rules. So that I believe that this is an application of rule eight.
按照规定。所以我相信这是第八条规则的应用。
We have a statement here that doesn't refer to x as and so whatever the value of
我们在这里有一条语句，它没有将x称为，所以不管值是多少
x was before the statement becomes the value of x after the statement so that
x在语句之前变成语句后的x值，因此
becomes x = three. And then, now we can see that this information is inconsistent.
变成x=3。然后，现在我们可以看到这个信息是不一致的。
The out of the statement here, is not consistent with the in of the statement
这里的Out of the Statement，与该语句的In不一致
here. In this case, you know, it's just one predecessor. And so, the, the value
这里。在这种情况下，你知道，它只是一个前身。所以，这个，这个价值
should be the same so x should be three. At this point And similarly x should be
应该是一样的，所以x应该是3。在这一点上，类似地，x应该是
three at this point. Here we have an assignment to a variable other than x.
在这一点上是三个人。这里我们对x以外的变量进行赋值。
That should, information should be the same before and after the statements, same
也就是说，语句前后的信息应该是一样的，应该是一样的
thing here. Now we have an assignment x. The point before that assignment is
这里的东西。现在我们有一个赋值x。赋值之前的点是
reachable and so sin ce this is a constant assignment we should know that x is that
由于这是一个常量赋值，我们应该知道x是
constant after the assignment. So here again we have a in and out issue so the
赋值后的常量。所以在这里我们又有了进进出出的问题
out of this statement is not consistent with the in of this statement. So this is
OUT OUT此语句与此语句的IN不一致。那么这就是
going to have to be updated but now, what should this be? Well, we have two
将不得不更新，但是现在，这应该是什么呢？嗯，我们有两个
inconsistent predecessors and so this has to be top and then finally, an assignment
不一致的前置任务，所以这必须是最上面的，最后是一个赋值
to x, sorry, an assignment to a state, to a variable other than x so the information
很抱歉，赋值给一个州，赋值给x以外的变量，所以信息
should just propagate across. And that, same is updated like this so now x is
应该直接传播到。同样的，也是这样更新的，所以现在x是
known to be top afterwards. And now, if we look around at all the program points,
后来被认为是最好的。现在，如果我们看看所有的节目点，
we'd see that all the information is consistent. All the rules, if you, if you,
我们会发现所有的信息都是一致的。所有的规则，如果你，如果你，
if you check whether the information before and after a statement or across a
如果检查语句前后或跨
statement. I'm sorry, or between predecessors and successors is correct,
声明。我很抱歉，或者说前任和继任者之间的关系是正确的，
it's correct everywhere according to the rules and so we're done.
按照规则，到处都是对的，所以我们就完了。